Christian Bingham.

Christian.Bingham@gmail.com Seattle, Washington 814.440.5467

about

Data-driven leader with experience spanning technology, consulting, and product management. Expert at building & maturing successful consulting teams, scaling high-touch Fortune 500 client relationships.

technical skills

Ad Tech (DSP, SSP, DMP, CDP, Data Lake), Cloud (SaaS, PaaS, IaaS), APIs, scripting, SQL, HTML, CSS, Unix/Linux, PHP, networking concepts, data ingest & delivery, taxonomy, digital profiling mechanics (cookie & MAID)

experience

Oracle

Principal Architect, Data Cloud

2018—Present

Data Cloud enables precise, person-level ad targeting & measurement at enterprise-scale

- Managing architectures for the industry's largest brands & media platforms. My applications span identity, privacy, and omni-channel messaging
- Integrating backend monetization systems, optimizing for scalability & minimal tech debt
- Implemented net-new client-facing consulting framework. Proven to drive renewals & increase overall stickiness
- Wrote open source library of command-line tools designed to streamline interactions with platform APIs

Upwardly Group

Director of Product and Implementation

2017-2018

Upwardly Group is an Ad Tech consulting collective

- Directed Programmatic business strategy, oversaw Trading & Finance teams
- Managed strategic partnerships, guided new platform relationships through all phases of the execution lifecycle (pitch, scoping, contract, implementation)
- Developed new financial models to better forecast client spend. Deployed in Q4 2017 to track budgets totaling over \$8MM. Using new processes, targets hit within 1.1% of target
- Instituted company-wide best practices, with the goal of optimizing toward portfolio growth and revenue expansion

Waypoint Media

Co-Founder, VP of Client Services

Acquired by FanAl 2013 – 2017

Waypoint was an ad platform purpose-built to monetize livestreaming media. We invented the unblockable in-stream video & banner ad formats.

- Acquired by Fan.ai
- At peak, our technology reached 45M viewers each month. Used by tier-1 streaming companies like Amazon & Twitch.tv to power live advertising needs
- Steered the company toward profitability, managed client go-to-market strategies
- Principal Design Product Manager: Led design & development of UI/UX, client media, Sales collateral

AppNexus

Senior Implementation Consultant, Global Accounts

Acquired by AT&T 2010 – 2013

AppNexus was the world's largest independent digital advertising platform

- Company's 70th employee. Led Publisher Integrations team: 12 direct reports
- Managed large-scale, technical enterprise relationships

• Product Manager for company's first server-to-server APIs, first video exchange product, developed private exchange best-practices, etc.

AppNexus London

Relocated to London to scale the company's first international Global Services team

- Drove 2x headcount growth
- Led hiring, training, continuity across international offices

Goldman Sachs

Financial Analyst, Global Control

2008 - 2010

Regulatory oversight for Asian & domestic security activity, weekly value ~\$2.5BN USD

 Founding member of an open source, internal Knowledgebase accessible to over 25,000 employees worldwide

hobbies

I love to tinker with hardware and hack around software. Past projects:

Open-Source Firewalls – Custom-built, solid-state appliances designed to protect networks against foreign traffic, malware, & suspicious activity

Bootloader Hacking – Installing OSes on unsupported hardware

education

Lehigh University

B.S., Mechanical Engineering